BRUNO MUNIZ

DATA ANALYTICS SENIOR • SÃO PAULO, BRAZIL • +55 22 998732277

• DETAILS •

São Paulo Brazil +55 22 998732277 brmunizmoura@gmail.com

LINKEDIN

linkedin.com/in/brunomuniz/

SKILLS

Problem-solving

Project management

Analytical ability

Report development

Power BI

Looker Studio

Google Analytics 4

Adobe Analytics

SQL

ETL

• LANGUAGES •

English, Portuguese

SUMMARY

My expertise is applying Business Intelligence & Growth techniques and methodologies supporting Strategy, Media and Data disciplines. Profile focused on data analysis to support strategic arguments and understanding the customers' behavior to optimize and identify new opportunities for the brand's success. Additionally, my expertise extends to a deep understanding of digital transformation, business objectives, and KPIs. Also have experience with Power BI, DAX, and SQL for business targeting, data visualization, and analysis purposes.

WORK HISTORY

ASIA, São Paulo - BI & Growth Supervisor

January 2024 to April 2024

Clients: GWM (China's largest private vehicle manufacturer) and Engie (a leading company in renewable energy in Brazil)

- Enabled the GWM and Engie to establish their specific business priorities in segmented Divisions by designing and implementing a tailor-made methodology considering the processes, strategies, and tools available.
- Identifying and defining relevant key performance indicators (KPIs) to monitor account performance and evaluate the success of growth strategies.
- Building a database with SQL for the accounts with multiple sources for historical information and future directions.

DAVID, São Paulo - Data Intelligence Specialist

October 2021 to January 2024

Clients: PlayStation, Burger King, and Toyota

- Act as the analytics lead for clients, actively participating in meetings with media and clients offering data-driven guidance and recommendations, developing analytical frameworks, and identifying data needs.
- Create Data Viz structures and manipulate data using tools such as Google Analytics, SQL, Looker Studio, and Power BI.
- Providing creation and maintenance of ETL load processes and technical guidance with documentation on BI projects to ensure data quality and standardization.

Babel-Azza, São Paulo - BI Analyst - Performance

July 2021 to September 2021

Clients: Atacadão (a company of the Carrefour Brazil Group and the largest Brazilian wholesaler in the number of stores) and Caedu (was the first retailer of clothing items and provided access to fashion to the C-class Brazilian family) and Sympla (

- Collaborate with the manager to analyze client KPIs and create a more effective media plan based on campaign purchase data.
- Develop dashboards based on defined KPIs and OKRs, and generate reports and insights for the media department

Babel-Azza, São Paulo - BI Assistant

August 2020 to July 2021

Clients: Atacadão and Caedu

- Production of reports and insights for the media area.
- Extraction and analysis of data from Google Analytics, Facebook, and Google platforms.
- Carrying out ad hoc studies and analyses.

FCB, São Paulo - Planning & CRM Assistant

June 2019 to August 2020

Clients: SKY (largest satellite pay TV operator in Brazil) and Leroy Merlin (brand is an integral part of ADEO the 3rd largest power in the construction materials sector in the world).

- Support the director and planning manager in creating strategies (product and institutional campaigns) for SKY and Leroy Merlin.
- Track public behavior to establish rules within the consumer journey and collaborate with service to create campaigns and relationship rules. Monitoring public behavior to design relationship rules within the consumer journey.
- Monitoring along with service and creation of campaigns and relationship rules.

DM9, São Paulo - Planning Assistant

August 2018 to May 2019

Clients: Itaú (the most valuable brand and largest company in the financial sector in Brazil), Seara (2nd largest producer and exporter of chicken and pork in Brazil), and Fiat (FCA)

- Briefing and monitoring with customer service, creation, and media, offering communication references and consumer needs.
- Participation in planning communications campaigns by benchmarking and desk research in the brand's categories.
- Monitoring the brand's categories and competition in all communication channels, targeting opportunities and risks.

EDUCATION

Degree in Advertising - Universidade Veiga de Almeida

January 2013 to June 2016

Specialization, Escola Conquer

July 2021 to November 2021

Specialization in Data Analysis with a focus:

- · Understanding of digital transformation, business objectives, and KPIs.
- · Statistical models and data for business targeting.
- Immersion in Power BI and use of DAX for data visualization, primary analysis, and hypothesis testing in decision-making.
- Basic concepts of SQL and Python (working with Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib, and Ploty).